Can you survive five nights?
Five Nights at Freddy's is a horror, thriller film directed by Emma Tammi.
Recently fired and desperate for work, a troubled young man named Mike agrees to take a position as
a night security guard at an abandoned theme restaurant: Freddy Fazbear's Pizzeria.
But he soon discovers that nothing at Freddy's is what it seems.
Mike, played by Josh Hutcherson.
Abby, played by Piper Rubio.
Vanessa, played by Elizabeth Lail.
Steve Raglan / William Afton, played by Matthew Lillard.
Aunt Jane, played by Mary Stuart Masterson.
Max, played by Kat Conner Sterling.
Five Nights at Freddy's is a 2023 American supernatural horror film
based on the video game series created by Scott Cawthon.
It was directed by Emma Tammi, and written by Cawthon, Tammi and Seth Cuddeback.
The film stars Josh Hutcherson as a troubled security guard who starts a job at an abandoned pizzeria where he discovers its
animatronic mascots are possessed by the souls of murdered children who were abducted by a serial killer decades before.
The film also stars Elizabeth Lail, Piper Rubio, Mary Stuart
Masterson, and Matthew Lillard feature in supporting roles.
Development of a Five Nights at Freddy's film adaptation
began in April 2015 under Warner Bros.
Roy Lee, Seth Grahame-Smith, and David Katzenberg were set to produce
it, with Gil Kenan announced as director and co-writer.
After multiple production delays, Kenan resigned from the project and
further development on the film was transferred from Warner Bros.
to Jason Blum's Blumhouse Productions in March 2017.
Chris Columbus was hired to direct and write the film in February 2018, ultimately
leaving the project and being replaced by Tammi in October 2022.
Principal photography occurred from February to April 2023
in New Orleans and surrounding communities.
Five Nights at Freddy's was simultaneously released for streaming on Peacock and
theatrically in the United States on October 27, 2023, by Universal Pictures.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and was a commercial success, grossing
$292–$297 million on a budget of $20 million and becoming Blumhouse's highest-grossing film.
A sequel, Five Nights at Freddy's 2, was released in 2025.
The film explores themes of night shift, child murder,
restaurant, custody battle, child in peril.
The tone is dark and intense.